MERRILL KOSHY THOMAS

+971-56-347-5735 / merrillkoshy@gmail.com / LinkedIn: in/merrill-koshy-thomas / Dubai, UAE

FULL STACK | MERNSTACK | JAMSTACK DEVELOPER

Full Stack Engineer with 6 years of hands-on experience designing, developing and implementing solutions using JavaScript. Successfully completed over 20 projects for userbases in millions. Orchestrated complete digital transitions of traditional businesses. Constantly updated with the latest development tools and practices.

Portfolio: https://merrillkoshy.github.io **GitHub**: https://github.com/merrillkoshy

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- Frontend, Backend, Databases, CI/CD
- Cross-Platform Mobile App Development
- Agile Methodologies & Development
- Project Management

- Wireframes, Storyboards & UI/UX
- Artworks & Creative Design
- Progressive Web Apps
- System & Solution Architecture

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Associate | Full Stack Developer

PricewaterhouseCoopers - Dubai, UAE

Sep 2021 – April 2022

Project: TAMM, an eGovernance service platform for the Abu Dhabi Government. Tasked with developing the user journey of Abu Dhabi Digital Authority (ADDA).

- Completely WFH Squad collaboration using Slack, Workspace, management using JIRA, GitLab, documented on Confluence.
- Development primarily in ReactJS, NodeJS and ExpressJS, utilizing Redux and Camunda, including API development and payment gateway integration.
- Engineered along with 4 other developers in a cross-functional team of 15, for the targeted journey.
- Integrated existing services to the newly developed unified platform thereby applying the latest UI trends, better UX, reducing the process steps & time required, clicks and redirections, inducing approximately a 50% increase in efficiency and exponential growth in the userbase.

Full Stack Developer

Freelance Development - Dubai, UAE

Mar 2021 - Sep 2021

Projects: Gulf Motorcycles Repairs & Rentals, United Piping Solutions, United International Piping UK, International Oilfield Supplies Oman, MarketPlace UAE

- Designed and developed websites, PWA admin panels, ERP systems using MERN and JAMstack, cross-platform mobile apps using React Native, online and print advertising campaigns [social media posts, logos, flyers, packaging, signboards, promotions] including video editing.
- Worked closely with managers and stakeholders for planning, designing and development iterations to ensure perfect delivery of planned products.
- Digitized 2 startups and a scaleup in a period of 6 months, singlehandedly delivering complete software and advertising solutions.

Full Stack Developer

Sana'a Kayum - Dubai, UAE

Jul 2019 - Mar 2021

- Responsible for digitizing the entire experience of Sana'a Kayum eCommerce website and in-house web (NextJS | ExpressJS) & mobile apps (React Native), databases (MongoDB, Firebase) and CI/CD (GitHub | Vercel).
- Close collaboration with stakeholders on every phase, studied market patterns and the cross-functional team (fashion designers, tailors, sales and marketing) to provide efficient solutions in the iterative development approach.
- Led and collaborated with a team of 3 developers.
- Creating a substantial increase in brand visibility, the online presence created multiple avenues of sales like the introduction to the retail market and creating several lines of clothing, collectively increasing revenue by approximately 120%.

+971-56-347-5735 / merrillkoshy@gmail.com / LinkedIn: in/merrill-koshy-thomas / Dubai, UAE

Web and Software Developer

Dot10 Technical Services - Dubai, UAE

Nov 2017 - Jul 2019

Responsible for managing the digital department of the company. Heading the department,

- Retained the existing client base and scaled their products.
- Won 6 new projects while leading a cross-functional team.

As a Full Stack Developer:

- Designed and developed websites and mobile apps for 11 projects [including Mercedes-Benz] using ReactJS, WordPress and Kotlin.
- Integrated payment gateways, online booking and client-provided APIs thereby scaling existing services.
- Created and led online and print advertising campaigns [social media posts, logos, flyers, signboards, promotions] using Adobe Photoshop and Illustrator, 3D modeling with SketchUp and video editing with Filmora.

Programmer

IPSR Solutions - Kerala, India

Feb 2017 - Sep 2017

Project: Site Health Checker

- Created an internal tool to inspect all the hosted sites of the company on their health checks with in-app reporting of site uptime and downtime, site traffic and hotspots thereby increasing service efficiency and reducing turnaround time.
- The project was built with Python using PyCharm and Tkinter, transitioning later to Kivy.
- Led by a Senior developer over a course of 8 months, inclusive of training.

Software Engineer

Soften technologies - Kerala, India

Jun 2016 – Jan 2017

Project: Travel with Glance

- Developed an Online Tourism Information System, which manages the user's trips, hotel stays and destinations with booking and time management.
- This included an Admin Module as well to onboard the user and facilitate the services provided.
- Built on C# and ASP.NET over a course of 8 months with 3 developers and a tech lead.

LANGUAGES, FRAMEWORKS & TOOLS

- ReactJS, React Native, NextJS, Razzle
- TypeScript, JavaScript, Jest, Enzyme
- Docker, GitHub, Gitlab, Travis CI
- JIRA, Confluence, Workspace, Slack
- Microservices & RabbitMQ

- NodeJS, ExpressJS, NestJS, Camunda
- MongoDB, Contentful, Strapi, Firebase
- Netlify, Vercel, Heroku, Google App Engine
- GraphQL, Redux, JWT, Redis Caching
- Progressive Web Apps

ADDITIONAL ACQUIRED SKILLS

- HTML5, CSS3, SASS, LESS
- Android Java, Kotlin
- Python, Django, Tkinter, Kivy
- Photoshop, Illustrator, in Vision

- ASP.NET, C#, C++
- PHP, WordPress, JQuery
- MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite
- Blender, SketchUp, Filmora

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology in Electronics & Communication Engineering

Mahatma Gandhi University

Jul 2015